Walter Sullivan Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- Alphabetical File, 1929-1995 (Box 184-214)
  - Volcanoes (Box 213)
    - Explosive, 1956-1975, 1983-1987, 1993, undated (Box 213)
    - Hawaii, 1957, 1978, 1987-1990, undated (Box 213)
    - Impacts, 1960, 1978-1994, (2 folders) (Box 214)
    - Kamchatka, 1976, 1983-1984, undated (Box 214)
    - Miscellany, 1979, 1987-1988, 1995 (Box 214)
    - Mount Saint Helens, 1980-1981 (Box 214)
  - Waste processing, 1990-1992 (Box 214)
  - Water (Box 214)
    - Anomalous, 1969-1971 (Box 214)
    - Drought and land cover, 1965, undated (Box 214)
    - Floods, 1973-1978 (Box 214)
    - Hudson Bay and James Bay, Canada, 1986 (Box 214)
    - Waves, 1975, undated (Box 214)
  - Water witching, 1944, 1965-1967 (Box 214)
  - Webster-Heise valve, 1981-1985 (Box 214)
  - Weightlessness, 1978-1987 (Box 214)
  - Whales, 1973-1989 (Box 214)
  - Whistlers, 1984-1987 (Box 214)
  - White dwarf stars, 1970 (Box 214)
  - White holes, 1978 (Box 214)
  - Writing, origin of, 1972-1981 (Box 214)
  - Zodiacal light, 1988 (Box 214)
- Digital Files, 1980-1993 (DF)
  The digital files include writings, draft copies of articles, draft correspondence, and documents related to the proposed “Landprints” television program. The bulk of the series contains Sullivan’s memoir drafts, recounting such experiences as expeditions to Antarctica, his service in the Navy during World War II, and time spent as a foreign correspondence in China, Korea, and Berlin. The series also includes files for "Terra Mobilis," a continental drift modeling program. At the time of processing many of the text file formats were inaccessible through available software. Files were most likely created on a WaveMate Bullet computer with a Control Program/Monitor (CP/M) operating system. This computer and these operating systems were popular in the late 1970s and early 1980s. As a result, these raw versions of the files do not appear as intended in their original hardware and software environments, and often include altered formatting and extraneous characters. Files can be opened with a text editor such as Notepad. Request files using the Digital ID.
  Arranged and described according to the series and subseries of the physical materials.
  - Personal File
    - Archives, Byrd Polar Research Center, Ohio State University, Columbus, Ohio, undated, 85555_080_013
    - Estate and trustee information, undated, 85555_080_011
    - Memoir drafts, circa 1980s, 1991-1993 See also Personal File, same title, 85555_079_005; 85555_079_006; 85555_079_008; 85555_079_010; 85555_079_011; 85555_080_001; 85555_080_002; 85555_080_003; 85555_080_004; 85555_080_005; 85555_080_006; 85555_080_007; 85555_080_008; 85555_080_009; 85555_080_012; 85555_080_013; 85555_080_014; 85555_080_015; 85555_080_016; 85555_080_017; 85555_080_018; 85555_080_019; 85555_080_020; 85555_080_021; 85555_080_022; 85555_080_023; 85555_080_024; 85555_080_026; 85555_080_027; 85555_080_028; 85555_080_029; 85555_080_030; 85555_080_031
  - Correspondence
    - Chronological, 1990 See also Correspondence, same title, 85555_080_012
  - Newspaper and Magazine Files
    - Raw copy and drafts, chronological, 1980s, 1991-1993 See also Newspaper and Magazine Files, same title, 85555_079_008; 85555_079_009; 85555_079_010; 85555_080_003; 85555_080_012
  - Television and Radio Files
    - "Landprints" See also Television and Radio Files, same title
      - Advisors, undated, 85555_080_023; 85555_080_026
      - Correspondence, circa 1988, 85555_080_006
      - Fund-raising, general, undated, 85555_080_012; 85555_080_014
      - Outlines, undated, 85555_080_013
  - Alphabetical File
    - Antarctica, tourism, 1993 See also Alphabetical Files, same title, 85555_079_003; 85555_079_005
    - Plate motions, Christopher Scotese, "Terra Mobilis" continental drift modeling program, 1989 (Container 201, Plate motions, Christopher Scotese), 85555_156_001; 85555_156_002
- Oversize, 1932-1984 (Box OV 1-5)
  Maps, posters, photographs, illustrations, and certificates.
  Arranged and described according to the series, container, and folders from which the items were removed.
  - Personal File
    - Cloudmaker maps showing Sullivan Ridge, Antarctica, 1964, 1967 (Box OV 5)
    - Posters (Container 8, Posters) (Box OV 2)
      - Antarctica slide show poster, undated (Box OV 2)
      - Emperor penguin photograph, undated (Box OV 2)
      - Groton School class photographs, 1932, 1934, 1935 (Box OV 2)
      - “Is Anyone Calling? poster,” undated (Box OV 2)
      - Yale University, 1940 class reunion photograph, 1965 (Box OV 2)
    - Lectures and television, poster for “Bicentennial dialogs, where do we go from here?” 1976 (Container 9, Lectures and television) (Box OV 3)
    - Memberships and committees, miscellany, certificate, “Knights of the Emperor Penguin Court membership certification,” 1976 (Container 13, Miscellany) (Box OV 3)
  - Book Files
    - Assault on the Unknown; the International Geophysical Year, photographs and illustrations (Container 68, Photographs and illustrations) (Box OV 2)
      - Illustration, Antarctica, undated (Box OV 2)
      - Map, "Karte der geographischen verbreitung des nordlichtes," geographic distribution of the northern lights, undated (Box OV 2)
      - Photograph, unidentified rocket launch, undated (Box OV 2)
    - Black Holes: The Edge of Space, the End of Time, photographs and illustrations, miscellany (Container 69, Miscellany) (Box OV 2)
      - Illustration, map depicting the area of a 1908 explosion in the Soviet Union, with annotations, undated (Box OV 2)
      - Illustration, "map of the tree blowdown pattern, from the findings of the 1961 expedition; Siberia, Soviet Union," with annotations, undated (Box OV 2)
      - Image of a newspaper, "The Black Hole," announcing a Massachusetts Institute of Technology Physics Colloquium by K. Brecher, Thursday, Feb. 14, 1974, Massachusetts Institute of Technology, Cambridge, Mass., undated (Box OV 2)
      - Photograph, black hole, with annotations, undated (Box OV 2)
    - Continents in Motion: The New Earth Debate
      - Miscellany (Container 82, Miscellany) (Box OV 5)
        - Map identifying features from the former suture zone between Europe and America, undated (Box OV 5)
        - Unidentified topographical map, undated (Box OV 5)
      - Photographs and illustrations, miscellany (Container 84, Miscellany)
        - Book jacket, second edition, undated (Box OV 1)
        - Images and layouts for book figures and illustrations, eighty-one total, undated (Box OV 1)
        - Images and layouts for book figures and illustrations, three total, undated (Box OV 3)
        - Map, highways of Canada and the northern U. S., undated (Box OV 1)
        - Photograph, "Jackson, W. H. 1278," undated (Box OV 1)
      - References and revisions, general, galley proof of book citations arranged by chapter, with annotations, undated (Container 92, General) (Box OV 2)
    - Landprints: On the Magnificent American Landscape, photographs and illustrations
      - Ice (Container 101, Ice) (Box OV 2)
        - Illustration, Great Lakes and surrounding states, undated (Box OV 2)
        - Illustration, migration of the Virginia Barrier Islands during the past 122 years; Drumstick Island formation; Westward migration of Core Bank, undated (Box OV 2)
      - Volcanoes, illustration depicting volcanic fields that have produced eruptions during the past five million years, undated (Container 103, Volcanoes) (Box OV 2)
      - Volcanoes and cascades (Container 103, Volcanoes and cascades) (Box OV 2)
        - Illustration, eastern U. S., related to figure 4-8, undated (Box OV 2)
        - Illustration, "Waves from the open sea," related to figure 27-1, undated (Box OV 2)
        - Photograph of a waterfall by Josef Scaylea, undated (Box OV 2)
      - Terranes (Container 104, Terranes) (Box OV 4)
        - Road map of British Columbia, Canada, undated (Box OV 4)
        - Two maps of terranes in the western U. S., with annotations, undated (Box OV 4)
    - Quest for a Continent: The Story of the Antarctic, map, "Antarctica, compiled from all available sources to 1943," 1947 (Container 109, Maps) (Box OV 5)
    - We Are Not Alone: The Search for Intelligent Life on Other Worlds and We Are Not Alone: The Continuing Search for Extraterrestial Intelligence
      - Miscellany (Container 120, Miscellany, 1960-1993, undated)
        - Certificate, "URKUNDE, Derinternational Sachbuchpreis" for We Are Not Alone, undated (Box OV 2)
        - Color print of early ideas of the solar system, undated (Box OV 3)
      - Reviews and publicity, poster, "Signale aus dem All: Auf der Suche nach belebtem Welten, Gibt es Leben im Weltraum? 1. Preis im Internationalen Sachbuch-Wettbewerb," undated (Container 123, Reviews and publicity) (Box OV 3)
  - Television and Radio Files, "Landprints," Miscellany, Map, Connecticut bedrock geological map, 1985 (Container 172, Miscellany) (Box OV 3)
  - Alphabetical Files
    - China, Chinese world map reproduction from Under Heaven Map Book, undated (Box OV 2)
    - Continental drift, maps depicting stages of continental drift, undated (Container 191, Continental drift) (Box OV 4)
    - "Earth at Night," poster, undated (Box OV 5)
    - Earthquakes, map, "Cal-Nev Quakes, 1980-1981," with annotations, circa 1982 (Box OV 4)
    - "Pilot chart of the North Pacific Ocean" published by the Hydrographic Office, Navy Department, 1948 (Box OV 5)
    - Soil conservation, map in six sections, "Mosaic imagery from Earth Resources Technology Satellite-1 of the conterminous U. S.; National Aeronautics and Space Administration Goddard Space Flight Center and the U. S. Department of Agriculture Soil Conservation Service," 1972 (Container 206, Soil conservation) (Box OV 4)
    - Tectonics, maps, "Generalized Tectonic Map of North America" by Philip B. King and Gertrude J. Edmonston, 1972 (Container 209, Maps) (Box OV 4)